

Java Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Core Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA, J2EE, JSP, JDBC, Angular JS, Bootstrap, CSS3, HTML



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Lowe's Services Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Java Developer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application

Maintenance, Solution Architecture, Core Java, Spring

Boot, Hibernate, JPA, J2EE, JSP, JDBC, Angular, Bootstrap, CSS3, HTML, Microsoft Azure, Spring JPA

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

Keen interest in Software Development and Web Development and possesses a proficiency in Java, Spring, Angular 6. Having 7.5 Years of experience in Core Java, Spring, spring Boot, Hibernate, Angular Js, Bootstrap, Knock out Js, JavaScript, JDBC, JSP, JQuery, HTML, Jasper Report, Java mail API, JQGRID, Spring JPA. High ability to work on Agile projects

Willing to update my knowledge and learn new skills to perform efficiently.

Work Experience

Lowe's Services as Senior Software Engineer Jul 2015 to Till Date

I am a Full stack Java developer, who is responsible to design and develop back end website applications ,ensuring responsiveness of applications, Designing and developing APIs, Designing user interactions on web pages, Build the frontend of applications through appealing visual design, Develop and manage well-functioning databases and applications, write technical documentation

Lowe's India Pvt Ltd, as Full stack Java Developer Jul 2015 to Jul 2015

Project I:

Project Name: Item Data Intake Period: Jan 2019 - till date

Project Description: Item Data Intake application keeps all new products initiate and enriches data information which comes to Lowe's from Vendor. Merchant take buying decision by filling all required enrich data in excel. User can search, upload and Export all initiation data.

Team Size : 5

Profile: Java developer/Front end Developer

Technologies: Spring (4.3), Angular 6, JAVA (Core), CSS, Type Script, HTML 5, Spring Boot, Spring JPA, Azure Cosmos

DB

Project II:

Project Name: PCM(Product Content Management), SAS, DQ application, PSSA, Permission App

Period: July 2015 - till date

Project Description: PCM is a Lowes internal system which is used to maintain a product data for an item. PSSA is a product specific selling attributes. DQ application is a data quality application which is used to compare the data of multiple applications which have same attribute. SAS application is used to generate the restriction on marketing data. Permission Application is used control the access and permission for a role related any functionality of other applications

Team Size: 11

Profile: Java developer/Front end Developer

Technologies: Spring (3.1, 4.0), Angular JS(1.5), JAVA (Core), Bootstrap, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, Knockout JS, HTML

5, Spring Boot, Spring JPA

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2012

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Core Java, spring, Spring Boot		
Hibernate, JPA, J2EE, JSP		
JDBC, Java mail API, Spring JPA		
Angular 6, Angular JS, Bootstrap		
CSS3, HTML, JavaScript		
J-Query, Jasper Report, JQGrid		
Tomcat 7.0.x, Apache-Ant		
WebSphere, Jboss 7.0		
MySQL 5.0, DB2		
Window 10		
Eclipse Mars, RAD, MySQL Query Browser		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time